<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<journal>
<entry date="2014-10-12">
<scripture book="2 Nephi" chapter="33" startverse="12"/>
<scripture book="Alma" chapter="30" startverse="18"/>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Repentance</topic>
<topic>Repentance</topic>
<content>This is the first entry.  Moroni is a boss in Alma Chapter 45.
I wish I could be like him someday.  He had a lot of faith and repentance.  He is a man.  I want to be a man.
Alma 30:18 is what it's all about.  Look up. Cool part 2 Nephi 33:12.  

 
It has several lines.
 
This is the last line
</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-10-13">
<scripture book="Helaman" chapter="10" startverse="10"/>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<content>Kishkumen is so dumb in Helaman 10:10.  I don't even think he is cool.  He is not like Jesus at all.
</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-11-03">
<scripture book="Matthew" chapter="21" startverse=""/>
<scripture book="Jacob" chapter="4" startverse="6"/>
<topic>Destruction</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Hope</topic>
<content>Something I have learned from this class is that Jesus was more recognized and loved than I previously thought.  In Matthew chapter 21 He rides into Jerusalem with a "very great multitude" that spread their garments and branches for Him to walk on.  I can relate this to today in the way that the church is big!  There are many members that love the Savior.  It's a good thing.  Only He can judge their hearts if they are true or not.  The advice that He then gives to the Pharisees is personal to each person listening.  In a way he makes everyone think by using children as an example.  The message being directed the accountable, excluded no one.


When Jesus cursed the fig tree, what was the meaning of it?
-I always thought it was supposed to make us think of the destruction that would quickly come to the wicked.  This time I got something additional.  I wrote a link to Jacob 4:6 where it says, “the very trees obey us”.  Perhaps Jesus was teaching two things at once, but I think this was an example of faith. 

I walk up and down a long flight of stairs Monday through Saturday.  While walking down last Friday, I thought of life and how it wouldn’t exist without Christ.  Then I thought of death and how it wouldn’t end if it weren’t for His resurrection.  I read the Bible Dictionary article about that on Sunday and it is so amazing that the resurrection is the center of our hope and that the resurrection of Jesus Christ is the most glorious of messages to all mankind.</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-11-05">
<scripture book="Matthew" chapter="24" startverse="12"/>
<scripture book="Matthew" chapter="24" startverse="27"/>
<topic>Destruction</topic>
<topic>Destruction</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<content>Stuck out from class:
Am I a checklist LDS or a true disciple LDS?  I think I am both right now.  I definitely was a checklist.  I don't think it's bad to be a checklist, but ONLY if the checklist has uncheckable boxes and two master boxes that cause nothing else to count unless those two boxes are checked.  The two master boxes would be: Love God and Love thy neighbor.  And maybe one big encapsulating box that is titled "Real Intent".  

In class I learned the meaning of carrying one's cross and that the Romans made the person carry their own cross.  Our hearts or wills can be so tough and reluctant.  These words must have been really meaningful from the Savior's mouth, because He would carry His own cross in just 5 days.

Reading:
The more I read about Jesus, the more I know Him.  Matthew chapter 24:12, "because of iniquity... the love of many shall wax cold." 13 says we will be saved if we endure.  JSM uses the term "steadfast" link to (Revelations 2:25-26). JSM clarifies that the tribulation will be on the Jews and the inhabitants if Jerusalem.  Matthew 24:27 says he will come really quick.  I think it means quicker than we can spread the message!  In JSM, the term "light" is used, not "lightning".  I watched Brother Wahlquist's devotional before reading this.  It went hand in hand on the subject of personal preparedness.  I am overwhelmed when reading about the second coming, but sticking to the basics consistently helps me to keep moving forward. 

Question:
Although, there is much that I am unsure of in this chapter, What is the abomination of desolation?

I think it is a time at the second coming when the wicked are destroyed.  I still don't completely understand.  I tried to go to Daniel and read it, but it will be something I will need to study more.  

Promptings: 
 I need to be praying vocally.  </content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-11-12">
<scripture book="3 Nephi" chapter="16" startverse="2"/>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<content>3 Nephi 16:2

Samuel the Lamanite was on top of a wall, having arrows and stones thrown at him by the unbelievers.

When our beliefs differ from others, sometimes they are angry and they revile against us.  

We can do what Samuel did and stand firm, trusting God that He will protect us from what they will throw.  It takes much faith, because sometimes it appears as if we will be knocked down by something, but we will be protected if we are obedient and stand firm.</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-11-12">
<scripture book="Helaman" chapter="16" startverse="2"/>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<content>Helaman 16:2

Samuel the Lamanite was on top of a wall, having arrows and stones thrown at him by the unbelievers.

When our beliefs differ from others, sometimes they are angry and they revile against us.  

We can do what Samuel did and stand firm, trusting God that He will protect us from what they will throw.  It takes much faith, because sometimes it appears as if we will be knocked down by something, but we will be protected if we are obedient and stand firm.</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-11-12">
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<content>From reading some letters from "The Screwtape Letters" today, I understand something new.  This earth is for us to develope our virtues.  Those who aren't fully put through this life need no strengthening.  There is great potential for us when we can learn to briddle passions.  This is the only way we can build and realize that we need God and Christ.  

Nothing physical would be necessary.  Blind men have known the Christ better than the students who studied the scriptures for a lifetime with only their physical eyes.</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-11-12">
<scripture book="Matthew" chapter="1" startverse="46"/>
<topic>Destruction</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Holy Ghost</topic>
<topic>Hope</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<content>Stuck out from class:
My question about the abomination of desolation was answered!  I somehow never understood what or when that was, but I am glad to know a little about it now and I want to go and read the writings of Josephus.  It is comforting to know that the holocost had nothing to do with God punishing the Jews.  I liked the steps we are given: watch, be faithful, and serve.  That was an answer to my other question!  Now it is a lot simpler that the first 19 verses are done and I know what to do in a general sense.  
Word count: 100

Reading:
Matthew Chapter 26
I made a footnote connecting Joseph-Smith-Matthew 1:46 to the word 'watch' in verse 38.  I love how the footnote Greek translation says stay awake.  
When I am going through the next trial, I hope I can think of the words from verse 39.  He fell on His face, prayed to the Father asking for it to pass, but then said what I think are the greatest words ever, "...nevertheless, not as I will, but as thou wilt".  I just finished reading "The Screwtape Letters" and it has explained why we have trials a lot more to me. 
When Jesus went back to Peter, He told him to watch and pray always.  Jesus just came from praying.  He is the perfect example.  
Word count: 124

Question:
I don't exactly understand what they were supposed to watch.  I know the footnote says to stay awake, but is that all it meant?  Could they have seen Judas walking by and stopped him from leading the Pharisees to Jesus or something?

Promptings: 
I felt the spirit in verse 38 and I now see how I can look to God in my challenges and ask for them to pass, but understand if they don't, for it is His plan and I know it is His will to strengthen me.</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-11-14">
<scripture book="3 Nephi" chapter="3" startverse="20"/>
<scripture book="3 Nephi" chapter="4" startverse="3"/>
<topic>Destruction</topic>
<content>3 Nephi 3:20-21
The people have plans, but obey their leader, who had instructions from the Lord.

3 Nephi 4:3
If they were not already obeying, they would have been destroyed by the Gadionton Robbers.</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-11-17">
<scripture book="John" chapter="15" startverse="19"/>
<scripture book="John" chapter="16" startverse="20"/>
<scripture book="John" chapter="14" startverse="13"/>
<scripture book="John" chapter="15" startverse="10"/>
<topic>Happiness</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<content>From class:
My favorite phrase from class was, "Tattoos and double piercings won't keep you out of heaven, but rebellion will."  Sometimes I wish I had something wise to say like that to all the people that ask silly questions.  It was interesting to look at the order of events around the last supper.  I learned that it is the bishop's job to know who is worthy and not let them partake of the sacrament if they are not.  I was always confused about that and I didn't want to smack it out of someone's hands even if I knew they were doing something wrong.  
Word count: 103

Reading:
I think in Matthew Chapter 14 through 16, Jesus is teaching His disciples to be able to use the Holy Ghost to follow Him once He leaves.  Matthew Chapter 15, without Him we are nothing.  I would hate to look back on my life and see that I struggled the whole time by myself.  It is so much better to grasp the hand of Christ and be supported and helped through trials and nourished through learning. I have a friend from Zimbabwe serving a mission there.  He recently told me how everyone is calling the missionaries and members in his area satanists.  John 15:19 reminded me of that ordeal and if people are reviling against us, it must mean we are doing the right thing.  John 16:20 is something I love.  It says they shall have sorrow because of what will happen, but it will be turned to joy because of what really is.
Word count: 154

Question:
Did the people at the time previous pray to Jehovah or Elohim?  

I think they prayed to Jehovah, the God of the Old Testament, but when did that switch? Did the Nephites at that time switch?  

I would think that they kept everything the same until he personally directed them, like in John 14:13 or 3 Nephi Chapter 18:20 (I just noticed that is a good reference number for praying, 1820), but I would like to hear about this more.

Promptings: 
John 15:10.  In my prayers recently, I have asked for opportunities to keep the commandments more fully.  I am keeping the basic ones, but I would like to magnify my responsibilities.  To abide in His love is a great reason to keep the commandments.  He loves us and Heavenly Father loves us, so why not!  When love and charity are combined with keeping the commandments, everything is good.</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-11-25">
<scripture book="Matthew" chapter="26" startverse="15"/>
<scripture book="Matthew" chapter="26" startverse="56"/>
<scripture book="Luke" chapter="22" startverse="34"/>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Pride</topic>
<topic>Covenants</topic>
<content>From class:
I need to be around good friends more often.  They shape who I am.  I habe a friend back home who I am going to spend less time with, although I will still talk to him to try and bring him back to church.  Christ surrounded Himself with good people.  A testimony is not all we need; We need to do.  In Luke 22:34, Jesus says "thou shalt" to Peter about how he will deny Him.  I am stuck on how He meant that.  I don't think Peter was a coward, but he may have doubted and during that doubt, valued his life or reputation above his confirming words of being close with Jesus.  It is something I fear.  I want to always stand firm.  Christ left 8 at the gate while He suffered in Gethsemane, because they were doubting.  I will try and not bring people that aren't supportive into my circle during tough times.
Word Count: 156

Reading:
While reading this for a second time within a week or two, one thing that stuck out to me was the word covenant in Matthew 26:15.  It was used in a secret combination way.  I never noticed how serious it may have been.  I always thought it was strange that Jesus told the disciples to go and tell a man they would be eating at his house.  I wonder how frightening it was for Judas to receive the answer confirming that he was to betray Jesus.  Did he know that Jesus knew and did he know what he would do?  
Word Count: 100

Question:
Matthew 26:56
I have always wondered how scriptures are so perfectly fulfilled and how the people use their agency to fulfill them.  How much thinking did Judas do while he was betraying the Savior?

I think in order to be a son of perdition he had to be perfectly aware of what he was doing.  I think the pride and anger in his heart pushed him that far.

Prompting:
I need to surround myself with good people.  That includes good girls.  I have been surrounded by a lot of debbie-downers lately.  I do have a friend named Phil that is the most positive person I know.  He smiles at everyone he sees and helps me to do the same.</content>
</entry>
<entry date="2014-12-01">
<scripture book="Moses" chapter="1" startverse="42"/>
<topic>Destruction</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Commandments</topic>
<topic>Faith</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Savior</topic>
<topic>Revelation</topic>
<topic>Revelation</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Love</topic>
<topic>Repentance</topic>
<topic>Repentance</topic>
<topic>Repentance</topic>
<topic>Holy Ghost</topic>
<topic>Hope</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<topic>Seek</topic>
<content>From class:
Class opened my eyes to how little there is about the atonement in the New Testament.  My trainer from my mission would always tell me how good the Book of Mormon is and how complete it is.  I really noticed this from class.  The four gospels barely differ in the wording used while Christ is suffering in Gethsemane.  There is no usage of the words "sin" or "every pore".  I read the first book of the "Chronicles of Narnia" over Thanksgiving Break and when Aslan is about to be killed, he is very quiet and wants to be alone for a while.  That is all other churches believe and now I understand why.  I wish I compared those two views before!
Word count:121

Reading:
Like in Brother Wahlquist's devotional, I liked D&amp;C 19:28 which states that it is a commandment for us to pray vocally as well as in our hearts.  I usually pray in whispers or a soft voice when I pray vocally.  I hope to get better and find a place where I could speak loud with no one hearing.  D&amp;C 19:38 says if we pray always we will have the spirit poured out upon us and our blessings will be greater than any earthly ones.  Mosiah Chapter 2 is one of my favorite chapters in the Book of Mormon.  I love the Humility that King Benjamin teaches.  It makes me think of how much Christ has done for us.  We wouldn't even be able to breath or move without him!  We can't boast or even say that we are as much as the dust!  All He asks us to do is keep His commandments.  Alma Chapter 7 is one that reveals more about what the atonement covers and how Christ felt every type of pain.  If we don't use the atonement then we are wasting it.  I love how much the Nephites knew about Christ even before He came to the earth.
Word count:201

Question:
D&amp;C 19:22 "...they must not know these things, lest they perish."
Is He talking about the things revealed in this chapter?  Are they considered more than repentance?  
I am not entirely sure.  I think He is talking about the fact that we will have to suffer for our sins if we do not repent.  It is a privilege to know this, but we don't always need to know the consequence to every law.  Also, as in Moses 1:42, He may have wanted this to stay quiet because there were doubters around at the time.

Prompting:
This Thanksgiving, I went home to California to visit my family.  On the way back I took a bus from Salt Lake to Rexburg.  I took a Book of Mormon with my testimony in it to give to someone I met while travelling.  While waiting for the bus, I sat next to a girl from China right in front of the Conference Center in Salt Lake.  She offered me a cigarrete and I told her why I don't smoke.  We got along well, but she wasn't interested about the church.  I thought she would sit by me on the bus, but she didn't.  Just when I was wondering if I had missed an opportunity I had prayed for that morning, a young man sat next to me.  He looked like a returned missionary.  He was clean, very smart and friendly, and has plans to be married soon.  We talked for hours and it was almost like we have been thinking the same thoughts for the past few months.  I had a feeling to talk about religion.  He is not a member, but is very familiar with the church.  We talked about so many of his questions about life and things he doesn't agree with in our doctrine.  I couldn't fully answer all of his questions, but he accepted the Book of Mormon.  He even asked for me to show him a couple of my favorite chapters.  I don't know what will happen, but I know that was an answer to my prayer.</content>
</entry>
</journal>
